<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>News by Krister Axel</title>
  <link>http://kristeraxel.com/</link>
  <description>The latest news from blog.kristeraxel.com.</description>
  <language>en-us</language>
  <pubDate>29 November 2012</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>Press</title>
        <link>Press</link>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a collection of press clips about my music from over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A review of &lt;a href=&quot;http://axelradio.com/album/sky-meet-sea&quot; title=&quot;Sky Meet Sea&quot;&gt;Sky Meet Sea&lt;/a&gt; November 2012&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evor.com/reviews_krister_axel.html&quot; title=&quot;EvO:R&quot;&gt;EvO:R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sky Meet Sea by Krister Axel&lt;br/&gt;
Reviewed by: Charles Harrelson&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;blockquote&gt;
 A lot can be said about a CD cover. You can look at a metal band you you might expect blood and guts vains and sharp claws. Maybe a country CD would have a horse on it and a pop band may have the band photo with everybody in full makeup. When you see a CD cover with a sunset you tend to think instrumental love songs or new age music. That was kind of what I expected when I popped Sky meets Sea into my CD player. 

To my surprise, track 1 was an indie rocker with a bit of a punk feel with lyrics sung by someone with a voice between Leon Redbone and Leon Russell. The music took me a few minutes to recover as I was expecting a soft flute with some seagulls and ocean breeze in the background.

After I recovered from the initial surprise I settled in and listened to one of the best Independent CD's released this year. Krister is a one man hit writing musician. He writes the music that gives you goose bumps and makes the hairs on your neck stand up. I found myself deeply involved with Before the Rain and Celebrate Tonight. Had either of these songs been written and performed by a Beatle it may have gone down as a song on par with &quot;Something&quot; or &quot;Yesterday.&quot;

Songwriting coaches should have this CD as required listening. Song structure is on par with any of the best songs written over the past 3 decades. I simply could not find anything wrong with this CD, other then the CD cover. This CD needs to be in everyones collection and in their i-Pod. You simply can not go wrong. I would have only wished the CD ended with Celebrate Tonight (not second to last). After a song like that you simply have nowhere else to go.
In the Studio:
Not much I can say about the studio mix. Other than it was brilliant. The bottom line was, this is a first class offering from lyrics, to song structure to performance and recording. 

Conclusion: 
This is clearly one of the best CD I have listened to this year! Great job Krister, you will be added to the top 25 Indie CD's. 

Clearly, 10 stars.......&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Collected reviews of &lt;a href=&quot;http://axelradio.com/album/arms-around-the-river&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Arms Around the River&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;
from iTunes 2007-2009&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.kristeraxel.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/aar_reviews.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.kristeraxel.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/aar_reviews-250x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;aar_reviews&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1283&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I guess the verdict is in on &lt;b&gt;Arms Around the River&lt;/b&gt;. It has proven to be in a pretty short time the album that has so far generated the best / most effusive reviews. 
It feels good to be getting recognized, I think there is a slow and steady rise going on here. I don't think it's a surprise that almost half of my sales now are coming from out of the country - mostly iTunes UK, Europe, and Australia. I love that I have no idea who any of these people are.
&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A review of &lt;a href=&quot;http://axelradio.com/album/arms-around-the-river&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Arms Around the River&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;
by CollectedSounds.com, December 2007
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
I already like an album that has a song called Impeach Bush.

These songs were written around the time of the London Terrorist attack in 2005. He was there and saw how it affected the people living in and around [London].

Axel has a sort of slow, drawly vocal style. His voice is very infectious. I could listen to it all day. The songwriting is bluesy, with lots of rhythm and heartfelt lyrics. Good stuff.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;




&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt; A review of &lt;a href=&quot;http://axelradio.com/album/arms-around-the-river&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Arms Around the River&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;
by IntelligentPop.com, August 2007
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Described as roots-rock and likened to the Dave Matthews Band in its press release, this artist actually reminds us more strongly of Gavin DeGraw and Randy Newman with their bluesy, bayou-accented singing styles... Axel has a lovely, warm voice, does not sound insincere, and achieves several moments of real beauty on this album. Overall, Axel belts less and sounds more sincere than other southern bluesmen. He’s generally mellow, which along with some lyrical and reverb-drenched electric guitar work is whence comes the dreamy beauty he sometimes achieves... The songwriting is thoroughly competent, the musicianship throughout is first-rate and the recording quality is terrific. Overall, a very strong effort. Nice work.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;




&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A live review was posted at &lt;a href=&quot;http://icecreamman.com/2007/02/krister-axel-at-the-hotel-cafe-in-hollywood/&quot;&gt;IceCreamMan.com&lt;/a&gt;  in FEB 2007&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;written by Jason Ricks&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table style=&quot;width:194px;&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;height:194px;background:url(https:///s/c/transparent_album_background.gif) no-repeat left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/krister.axel/2007Hotel?authkey=Gv1sRgCJzTjdLzkoqFBQ&amp;feat=embedwebsite&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/_aJ4urxfgN9A/TXM45lKPZnE/AAAAAAAAIjQ/inanS0LAoyM/s160-c/2007Hotel.jpg&quot; width=&quot;160&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; style=&quot;margin:1px 0 0 4px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:center;font-family:arial,sans-serif;font-size:11px&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/krister.axel/2007Hotel?authkey=Gv1sRgCJzTjdLzkoqFBQ&amp;feat=embedwebsite&quot; style=&quot;color:#4D4D4D;font-weight:bold;text-decoration:none;&quot;&gt;2007-hotel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;




&lt;blockquote&gt;

From the outside, the Hotel Cafe is an unassuming grayish building with a small sign on the front door directing visitors to the alley next to the building. Another sign on the side of the building leads you down a long, unremarkable alley to the back entrance. Once inside, you’re treated to a comfortable, hip atmosphere-dim lighting, a dark wooden bar, exposed brick walls, and red velvet curtains.

It’s a fitting place for musician-singer-songwriter Krister Axel to celebrate the release of his new CD, Arms Around the River. Like the building in which he’s playing, Krister and his band make a modest sight onstage-they appear more like a group of friends playing a friend’s party than a gig in the heart of Hollywood. But just seconds into the first song, “Head in the Rain,” their professional musicianship and talent is immediately and pleasingly apparent. The earthy, roots rocking combination of acoustic and electric guitar, organ, harmonica, and solid rhythm section is infectious and easy to like. After the first verse, you’re hooked. The song rises from Krister singing soft lyrics over his solo organ to a spirited and full sounding all instruments jam, the mood of the music changing with the complexity and intensity of the sound.

Moments later, “True Believer” makes me think I’ve heard this band before, but where? I know they get no radio play, Krister produced his own album, and I happen to know he has a day job. There is something very familiar about these songs-the poignant earnestness of his writing is very appealing and easy with which to identify. This touching earnestness comes out again in the next song, “Stay,” which is a beautiful ballad that is very emotive-the kind of music that can make you rethink an argument with a loved one, or turn that afternoon’s road rage into a silly, distant memory. The mood of the melody is slow and sad-mostly expressing personal longing-that somehow manages to convey an inspiring notion of graceful wisdom throughout. It’s also packaged between an upbeat intro and a hopeful closing riff that leaves the listener feeling extremely satisfied. This is serious hit song material; original music that is at once evocative of Dave Matthews, Coldplay and Blues Traveler.

And so the evening passed. Song after song, Krister and his band continuing to impress with a range of interesting and intricately constructed songs replete with tight stops, tempo changes, tasty hooks, and interesting personal lyrics. After playing the first five songs from his new album, Krister (playing acoustic guitar) and the band (Karen Teperberg on drums, Matt Delvecchio on bass, and Mike Freas on electric guitar, and guest Nick Blechman on mandolin) played a brand new, as yet unrecorded song, that is a lot of fun and slightly reminiscent of The Cars.

Krister Axel is not your typical Hollywood performer-he’s not trying to be anyone or anything, he just plays what he feels, and it is good. He plays earnest songs from the heart, like the touching ballad written for his sister’s wedding, “Something Beautiful.” His enthusiasm onstage when interacting with the audience is also very evident and engaging. The only complaint one could have about Krister’s music is that his songs are too short, especially for live performance. This became more evident during the band’s finale, “I’m the Gun,” a strong blues number featuring the dueling harmonicas of guests Judy Rudin (who also played on the first few songs of the set) and Chet Dixon, in which the whole band treated the crowd to a raucous extended jam that was by far the most fun of the evening.

Not to say that the rest of the show wasn’t fun-in fact every song is great. Krister Axel and his band play a rootsy, sometimes poppy, blues-influenced rock and roll that is impossible not to like. We could all stand to hear more of this music. Somebody give this guy a distribution deal please!

&lt;/blockquote&gt;




&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;A review of &lt;a href=&quot;http://axelradio.com/album/arms-around-the-river&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Arms Around the River&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;
by RandomTracks.com, May 2008
&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Krister Axel is a self taught musician, poet, and songwriter based out of Los Angeles. His appealing voice is the perfect delivery apparatus for his roots based southern rock music.
The album is incredibly well produced. The sound quality is excellent and [the] music is a perfect accompaniment to long road trips and days when you just want the earthy sound that is Krister Axel. [A] smooth and classic southern rock sound.
Track 2, &quot;True Believer&quot;... is probably my most favorite from the album. It is certainly the one that keeps ringing in my head... the production is amazing.
Track 8, &quot;I'm the Gun,&quot; kicks things off with some nice rhythm guitar work that also brings the tempo up a bit. [This song is] well constructed with alternating instrumentation and drum riffs [that] add a lot of musical interest. The Nashville/blues influences clearly shine through. Great backing vocals, and some interesting vocal layering, add an extra dimension at the end.
The last track, &quot;Impeach Bush&quot; is a political song that made me think of an updated Woody Guthrie, very different than the rest of the album. Axel delivers that message of change in a very appealing and musically solid way.
Krister Axel's Arms around the River is a solid southern rock album that has rightfully earned a permanent place in my CD collection, and has become a frequent visitor in my car's CD player.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;




&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Sean McCallum (from &lt;a href=&quot;http://seanmccallum.blogspot.com/2007/06/best-of-nxne.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;seanmccallum.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;) names an award after me.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;table style=&quot;width:auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/N8w2iSVgeHUj04686WYJJAr6HSCqd1U1OYY-4hh2JJY?feat=embedwebsite&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_aJ4urxfgN9A/TXXt3zLtmTI/AAAAAAAAIus/HUxqbfusjsE/s400/ka_extra2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:11px; text-align:right&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;table style=&quot;width:auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/6U-LlAjE1HCRNWpQnft4dAr6HSCqd1U1OYY-4hh2JJY?feat=embedwebsite&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_aJ4urxfgN9A/TXXt30J0iEI/AAAAAAAAIus/tnp2rnudx2k/s400/ka_extra1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:11px; text-align:right&quot;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon Jan 01 00:00:00 -0800 1900</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Info</title>
        <link>Info</link>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First of all, if you are looking for music or lyrics to one my songs, click &lt;a href=&quot;http://axelradio.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a site full of stuff I have written &lt;a href=&quot;/Archive&quot;&gt;over the years&lt;/a&gt;. I have old journal posts, some citizen journalism, the occasional 'essay', and lots of code/geek stuff. I also put up song posts for &lt;a href=&quot;/category/RockstarAlley/&quot;&gt;my podcast&lt;/a&gt;. For a while I was supporting two different blog sites but I finally consolidated and you can read about the drama &lt;a href=&quot;/2009/04/and-now-we-can-talk-about-it/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I make a living as a software engineer which you can learn about at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/in/kristeraxel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a look around and if you want you can say &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;hello&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A little more about me (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krister_Axel&quot;&gt;from wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Krister Axel, born in Paris, has been writing and performing roots and blues music for 20 years. He began his career as a songwriter performing in the streets of Paris, then New York City, Madison and finally Los Angeles. Krister Axel claims the legendary Chris Whitley as the greatest influence on his writing. His work encompasses pop songwriting as well as a roots-based approach to instrumental pieces commissioned for movie projects. His credits include pieces for the soundtracks to Hate Crime and A Colombia and licensing with NBC Networks, Regent Theaters, and many others. Most recently, Krister had a few songs placed on the season 5 dvd of Friday Night Lights (TV series) which has been very successful in generating interest about his music. These songs are Illuminate the Sky and Georgia Rain (both from the EP Swexico), as well as Something Beautiful from the album Arms Around the River.

Krister Axel has a unique style of singing, described by fans as a sort of Bill Withers meets Jamiroquai. He is a self-taught musician who started on the piano and eventually discovered the acoustic guitar.&lt;/blockquote&gt;




&lt;p class=&quot;ac&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.kristeraxel.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Krister_axel_sf07.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.kristeraxel.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Krister_axel_sf07-221x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Krister_axel_sf07&quot; width=&quot;221&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; class=&quot;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p class=&quot;ac&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;sweet photo by Shanti Wilson&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon Jan 01 00:00:00 -0800 1900</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Contact</title>
        <link>Contact</link>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;contact_table_p&quot;&gt;
  &lt;table id=&quot;contact_table&quot;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;
      It is probably fastest to contact me through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/in/kristeraxel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to employ me, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/music.krister.axel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to be my friend. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/kristeraxel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; is also a good way to go but it is probably the slowest because I sometimes don't check my account for a few days or even a week or two at a time.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
  It all depends on how quickly you need a response. You can find out more about me &lt;a href=&quot;/Info&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or on any of these social networks:&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;
        &lt;p class=&quot;contact&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/music.krister.axel&quot; title=&quot;Krister Axel on Facebook&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/facebook.png&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; alt=&quot;Krister Axel on Facebook&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/kristeraxel&quot; title=&quot;Krister Axel on Twitter&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/twitter.png&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; alt=&quot;Krister Axel on Twitter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://klout.com/kristeraxel&quot; title=&quot;the Klout score for Krister Axel&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/klout.jpg&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; alt=&quot;the Klout score for Krister Axel&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/in/kristeraxel&quot; title=&quot;Krister Axel on LinkedIn&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/linkedin.jpg&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; alt=&quot;Krister Axel on LinkedIn&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/artist/krister-axel/id16710514&quot; title=&quot;Krister Axel on iTunes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/itunes_logo-315x315.png&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; alt=&quot;Krister Axel on iTunes&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://axelradio.com&quot; title=&quot;Listen to and buy Krister Axel songs on Bandcamp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/bandcamp2.png&quot; width=&quot;80&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; alt=&quot;Listen to and buy Krister Axel songs on Bandcamp&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://axel.me/g&quot; title=&quot;Krister Axel on Google +&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/plus-icon-48x48.png&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; alt=&quot;Krister Axel on Google +&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href=&quot;http://axel.me/mouse&quot; title=&quot;Krister Axel on rebelmouse&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/img/rebel1s.jpg&quot; width=&quot;30&quot; height=&quot;30&quot; alt=&quot;view my media stream at rebelmouse&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon Jan 01 00:00:00 -0800 1900</pubDate>
      </item>
    
</channel>
</rss>